RICHARD MONFORT

135 North Pearl Street | Brockton, MA 02301

(774) 297-4742 | richard.s.monfort@gmail.com | rmonfort.github.io | www.linkedin.com/in/rmonfort

SUMMARY

A self-taught software developer with over a year of professional experience. Interests and personal areas of study include web and .NET technologies such as HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, C#, and ASP.NET MVC 5. Leverages both formal and informal training to provide software and hardware expertise.

SKILLS

Languages – HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Tcl, Expect
Operating Systems – Windows, Linux, Mac OS
Software – Visual Studio
Hardware – PC hardware design and setup
Methodologies – Agile software development
General – Technical writing, analytical problem solving, working in teams, working independently

KEY ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- ☑ Successfully delivered business process management solution to the client within the 6 month time frame
- ☑ Successfully built a fully functional device within a 4 month time frame on a 3 member team
- ☑ Identified and troubleshot various software and hardware issues in a timely manner reducing overall client downtime

PERSONAL PROJECTS

GitHub

github.com/rmonfort

Shunting-yard Algorithm (2014) - A C++ implementation of the Shunting-yard algorithm. C++

Write Out Number (2014) - A program that asks the user for an integer and then writes out the number in plain English using a recursive function. C#

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING TECHNOLOGY from Wentworth Institute of Technology (2007-2011), Boston, MA

- WIT Merit Award Scholarship, Dean's List Fall 2009
- Undergraduate Coursework: Technical Communications, Object-Oriented Programming with C++, Microcontrollers & Embedded Communications, Computer Systems Architecture, Computer Communications & Networks, Computer Science I using C, Intro to Operating Systems

PROJECTS

Automatic Window Blinds (2011) - A device that opened and closed window blinds based on the temperature of the room and the amount of light outside. It used a single-board microcontroller in conjunction with a temperature sensor, a light sensor, and a rotary motor. Source code was written in C++.

- Resolved a motor overheating issue by adding sufficient delays to source code
- Successfully built a fully functional device within a 4 month time frame on a 3 member team

PROFESSIONAL TRAINING

BOOKS

HTML and CSS - Design and Build Website, C++ Primer (5th Edition), Data Structures & Algorithms in C++ (2nd Edition), Think Like a Programmer: An Introduction to Creative Problem Solving, Clean Code - A Handbook of Agile Software Craftsmanship, Pro C# 5.0 and the .NET 4.5 Framework (6th Edition) Pro ASP.NET MVC 5

PLURALSIGHT

C# Fundamentals with C# 5.0, Relational Database Design, HTML5 Fundamentals, HTML5 Advanced Topics, CSS3 In-Depth, JavaScript Fundamentals, Building Applications with ASP.NET MVC 4, ASP.NET MVC 4 Fundamentals, ASP.NET MVC 5 Fundamentals

EXPERIENCE

WEB DEVELOPER - Harvard Business School - Oct. 2014 to Nov. 2014

- Created and maintained web forms for various courses using HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript
- Trained coworkers in the use of Certain event management software
- Created and maintained documentation for Certain event management software so anyone could learn to use it

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER - Accenture - Oct. 2012 to Sept. 2013

- Designed user interfaces for various projects based on client requirements using HTML5, CSS3, and PEGA PRPC
- Utilized various agile practices such as backlogs, user stories, and iterative and incremental development
- Trained new coworkers in user interface design using HTML5, CSS3, and PEGA PRPC

PROJECTS

Health Insurance (2012-2013) – A business process management application that streamlines health insurance registration and maintenance.

Role: UI Developer

Team: 14 members (3 frontend, 4 middleware, 4 backend, 3 project management)

- Resolved an issue involving lack of UI consistency by creating templates for regular use and encouraging coworkers to do the same
- Learned HTML5 and CSS3 in order to provide UI customizations requested by client
- Successfully delivered the product to the client within the 6 month time frame

IT SERVICE DESK SUPPORT - Instron - Nov. 2011 to Jan. 2012

- Identified and troubleshot various software and hardware issues in a timely manner reducing overall client downtime
- Created and managed user accounts through active directory
- Maintained records of system changes and performed backups and file recovery
- Deployed services and systems using Symantec Ghost to fulfill needs of organization

IIT INTERN – Museum of Science – Sept. 2010 to Dec. 2010

- Identified and troubleshot various software and hardware issues
- Created and managed user accounts through active directory

QA INTERN – Tatara Systems – Jan. 2010 to Apr. 2010

- Developed various scripts using Tcl and Expect to increase efficiency of work place
- Organized and maintained various documentation